{"tossups": [{"question": "A character who  rst appeared in this poem is reimagined as the tribal elder T'kama in a 1993 novel by Andre\u0301 Brink couched as that character's \" rst life.\" Tethys offers a Ptolemaic (toh-leh-MAY-ik) account of the universe at a feast on the Isle of Love in the penultimate canto of this poem, whose  nal canto includes a description of the \"machine of the world.\" The actions of a group of men in this poem cause Bacchus to urge Neptune to convene a council of sea gods. Characters in this poem are discouraged by the Old Man of Restelo and menaced by a monstrous personi cation of the Cape of Good Hope called Adamastor on their way to Calicut. Vasco da Gama's voyage to India is  ctionalized in, for 10 points, what poem by Lui\u0301s de Camo\u0303es (loo-EES \"day\" kah-MOH-ens) that serves as the national epic of Portugal?", "answer": "The Lusiads [or Os Lusi\u0301adas]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Lusiads</u></b> [or <b><u>Os Lusi\u0301adas</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The Lusiads", "Lusiads", "Os Lusi\u0301adas"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "At a beauty pageant in this city that was held in a basement, a group of women li ed up a banner that read \"don't let them kill us!\" A cellist in this city performed Tomaso Albinoni's Adagio in G Minor in the ruins of bombed-out buildings. Scars le  by mortar shells in this city were  lled with red resin to create its namesake \"roses.\" During a siege of this city, injured civilians were evacuated by airli  in Operation Irma. The couple Admira Ismic (ahd-MEE-rah IZ-\"mitch\") and Bosko Brkic (BOH-sko BURR-kitch) were killed while crossing this city's Vrbanja (vurr-BAHN-yah) Bridge. Painted signs reading \"pazi!\" (paht-zee), or \"watch out!,\" were common in this city's \"Sniper Alley.\" A nearly four-year siege of this city was li ed by the Dayton Accords. For 10 points, what city, which was besieged from 1992 to 1996 by ethnic Serbs, is the capital of Bosnia and Herzegovina?", "answer": "Sarajevo (sah-rah-YAY-voh)", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Sarajevo</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Sarajevo", "Sarajevo"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "sah-rah-YAY-voh"}, {"question": "R. rubrum oxidizes this compound with water to make hydrogen. Cytochrome P\u00c2\u00b7450 is named for its max absorbance wavelength when bound to this compound. In the Wood\u00c2\u2013Ljungdahl (L'YOUNG-\"doll\") pathway, this compound is methylated and then attacked by sulfur to make acetyl-CoA (uh-SEE-til-KOH-ay). This compound is the lightest product of the reaction that causes bruise coloration; in that reaction, this compound, ferrous iron, and biliverdin form when heme degrades. Like cyanides and azides, this compound inhibits cytochrome c oxidase in the ETC. This compound shi s a plot of \"pO2 (pee-oh-\"two\") versus percent saturation\" way le , which is dangerous because pulse oximetry cannot differentiate it from O2, even though its af nity is 250 times higher. For 10 points, what poisonous gas competes with oxygen for binding to hemoglobin?", "answer": " carbon monoxide [or CO]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>carbon monoxide</u></b> [or <b><u>CO</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["carbon monoxide", "carbon monoxide", "CO"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A  lm from this country opens with a dream sequence in which the title character meets Jane Birkin, who delights the title character by saying that she looks like Birkin's daughter, Charlotte Gainsbourg. This country provides the setting of In Another Country, which consists of three episodes in which the same French woman, played by Isabelle Huppert, meets a beach lifeguard. A director from this country  lmed a tracking shot along a corridor in which a man  ghts off an entire gang with just a hammer. That director adapted Sarah Waters's Victorian-era novel Fingersmith into this country's colonial era for 2016's The Handmaiden. In a  lm from this country, a man is imprisoned in a hotel room for 15 years before being tricked into sleeping with his daughter. For 10 points, name this home country of Oldboy director Park Chan-Wook.", "answer": "South Korea [or Republic of Korea; or ROK; prompt on \"Korea\"]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>South Korea</u></b> [or <b><u>Republic of Korea</u></b>; or <b><u>ROK</u></b>; prompt on <u>Korea</u>]", "acceptable": ["South Korea", "Republic of Korea", "ROK"], "promptable": ["Korea"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A contemporary \"renovation movement\" named a er this man uses his trademark giant cowboy hat as its symbol. \"Yank\" Levy's theories of guerrilla warfare were informed by his time serving as a gunrunner for this man's army in the early 1920s. This supporter of President Juan Bautista Sacasa unsuccessfully worked with Sacasa to limit the power of his country's Guardia Nacional. At the end of his country's Constitutionalist War, this general refused to lay down his arms and instead waged a guerrilla war against the U.S. Marines occupying his country. This man, who was assassinated in 1934 by Anastasio Somoza's troops, inspired a guerrilla movement led by Daniel Ortega. For 10 points, name this Nicaraguan bandit, the namesake of a socialist party that warred with the Contras.", "answer": "Augusto Ce\u0301sar Sandino [or Augusto Nicola\u0301s Sandino; do not accept or prompt on answers mentioning \"Sandinista(s)\"]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Augusto Ce\u0301sar Sandino</u></b> [or <b><u>Augusto Nicola\u0301s Sandino</u></b>; do not accept or prompt on \"answers mentioning \"Sandinista(s)\"]", "acceptable": ["Augusto Ce\u0301sar Sandino", "Augusto Ce\u0301sar Sandino", "Augusto Nicola\u0301s Sandino"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["answers mentioning \"Sandinista(s)"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Mishnah states that Rabban Gamaliel posted diagrams of this object to assist the hediot, who were people who offered testimony about this object and were asked  ve questions about it. At a courtyard called Beit Ya'azek (beht yah-ahzek), the proclamation of \"mekudash\" (meh-koo-dahsh) was issued a er the Sanhedrin cross-examined people about this object. Prior to the reforms of Hillel II, a process of \"sancti cation,\" or \"kiddush kachodesh\" (kih-DOOSH ka-HO-desh) required two people to see this object a er its \"birth,\" or \"molad\" (moh-lahd). A period known as \"Rosh Chodesh\" (rohsh HO-desh) begins a er this object emerges from conjugation. In the twel h chapter of Exodus, God speaks to Moses on the  rst of Nissan and says that each month begins with the emergence of this object. For 10 points, what celestial body's \"new\" phase determines the Jewish calendar?", "answer": "Moon [or Luna; or yerah-ah; or levanah; or sahar; accept new moon or crescent moon]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Moon</u></b> [or <b><u>Luna</u></b>; or <b><u>yerah-ah</u></b>; or <b><u>levanah</u></b>; or <b><u>sahar</u></b>; accept <b><u>new moon</u></b> or <b><u>crescent moon</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Moon", "Moon", "Luna", "yerah-ah", "levanah", "sahar", "new moon", "crescent moon"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this work, \"Knot Taps\" are shown graf ti-ing buildings with the outlines of lovers embracing as if vaporized by the blast at Hiroshima. A story-within-a-story in this work describes a man trying to warn his town of attacking pirates from the Black Freighter. The chapters \"The Abyss Gazes Also\" and \"A Stronger Loving World\" appear in this work, whose twel h and  nal chapter opens with the image of a clock striking midnight with its face covered in blood. Near the beginning of this work, the protagonist investigates the death of the Comedian, which turns out to be the result of a plot instigated by Adrian Veidt (VITE). A er failing to stop Ozymandias, Rorschach is vaporized by the blue-skinned superhero Dr. Manhattan at the end of, for 10 points, what serialized graphic novel by Alan Moore?", "answer": "Watchmen", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Watchmen</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Watchmen", "Watchmen"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A function denoted by this term can be split into upper and lower incomplete functions. For inputs of \"one minus x\" and \"x,\" the product of a function denoted by this term satis es the Euler re ection formula. The sequence of arrival times, but not inter-arrival times, of a Poisson process has a distribution denoted by this term. If the distribution denoted by this term has shape parameter \"n over two\" and rate parameter one-half, it is a chi-squared distribution with n degrees of freedom. For an input k, a function denoted by this letter is de ned as the integral from zero to in nity of \"x to the k minus one\" times \"e to the minus x dx.\" A function generalizing the factorial to real and complex arguments is denoted by, for 10 points, what third letter of the Greek alphabet?", "answer": "gamma [accept gamma function or gamma distribution]", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>gamma</u></b> [accept <b><u>gamma function</u></b> or <b><u>gamma distribution</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["gamma", "gamma", "gamma function", "gamma distribution"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Studies for this painting that show a sailor holding a vase at the center and a medical student holding a skull and entering from the le  were discussed in a 1972 essay on this painting's \"philosophical\" nature, which was written by Leo Steinberg. The artist and his friends joked that two of this painting's subjects were the artist's girlfriend and Max Jacob's (mahks ZHAH-kob's) grandmother. This work, which borrows from its artist's earlier Two Nudes, depicts a woman in the back right who enters through a part in a blue curtain. A pile of fruit sits in the bottom center of this painting, whose two rightmost subjects have facial features inspired by African masks. For 10 points, name this painting by Pablo Picasso that depicts  ve prostitutes and has a title referencing a French city.", "answer": "Les Demoiselles d'Avignon [or The Young Ladies of Avignon; accept The Brothel of Avignon]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Les Demoiselles d'Avignon</u></b> [or <b><u>The Young Ladies of Avignon</u></b>; accept <b><u>The Brothel of Avignon</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Les Demoiselles d'Avignon", "Les Demoiselles d'Avignon", "The Young Ladies of Avignon", "The Brothel of Avignon"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This figure shares his name with an Argonaut who founded the city of Cius (KY-us) after being left near Pegae (peh-\"GUY\") to help Heracles search for Hylas. According to Appian's Illyrian Wars, this figure fathered Celtus, Illyrius, and Galas (KEL-tus, \"ill EAR\"-ee-us, and GAH-las), each of whom founded a namesake tribe. After this figure threw a boulder near the slopes of Mount Etna, a river god was born from the blood of a youth who was crushed by the falling rock. This figure killed Acis (AY-\"kiss\") out of jealousy because Acis loved the nymph Galatea. A group of men escaped from this figure by clinging to the bellies of rams as they fled out of his cave. After being blinded by a hot stake, this monster cried that \"Outis\" (OO-tiss), or \"Nobody,\" had attacked him. For 10 points, what son of Poseidon was a Cyclops who cursed Odysseus with a long voyage back to Ithaca?", "answer": "Polyphemus [or Polyphemos]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Polyphemus</u></b> [or <b><u>Polyphemos</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Polyphemus", "Polyphemus", "Polyphemos"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The U.S. negotiated a treaty with this tribe to allow the construction of a mail route that was called, like a more northerly route, the Federal Road. During the Civil War, a chief of this tribe named Opothle Yohola (oh-pohth-lay yo-\"HOLE\"-uh) led an escape to Kansas called the \"Trail of Blood on Ice.\" This tribe negotiated with the U.S. through Benjamin Hawkins and signed two treaties with the government that were named for Indian Springs. Under the command of Chief William Weatherford, members of this tribe avenged their defeat at the Battle of Burnt Corn by massacring the garrison at Fort Mims. Davy Crockett fought this tribe in a war ended by the Treaty of Fort Jackson. The Battle of Horseshoe Bend was lost by, for 10 points, what tribe whose Red Stick faction fought a war against the U.S. in the 1810s?", "answer": "Creek Confederacy [or Creeks; or Creek tribe; or Muscogee(s); or Mvskoke; do not accept or prompt on \"White Sticks\" or \"Red Sticks\"]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Creek Confederacy</u></b> [or <b><u>Creeks</u></b>; or <b><u>Creek tribe</u></b>; or <b><u>Muscogee(s)</u></b>; or <b><u>Mvskoke</u></b>; do not accept or prompt on \"White Sticks\" or \"Red Sticks\"]", "acceptable": ["Creek Confederacy", "Creek Confederacy", "Creeks", "Creek tribe", "Muscogee(s)", "Mvskoke"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["White Sticks", "Red Sticks"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author warned of an enemy who knows \"your heart is luminous / in the watched dark\" and will \"shut the sun\" to become \"the last Samson of your zodiac\" in a poem set \"on almost the incendiary eve.\" This poet wrote that he must enter \"the synagogue of the ear of corn\" but will not give \"any further / elegy of innocence and youth\" in a poem that concludes \"a er the  rst death, there is no other.\" This man gave those poems about the London Blitz the titles \"Deaths and Entrances\" and \"A Refusal to Mourn the Death, by Fire, of a Child in London.\" In another poem, he wrote that \"wise men at their end know dark is right\" and that \"old age should burn and rave at close of day.\" For 10 points, name this heavy-drinking Welsh poet of \"Do not go gentle into that good night.\"", "answer": "Dylan Thomas [or Dylan Marlais Thomas]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Dylan Thomas</u></b> [or <b><u>Dylan Marlais Thomas</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Dylan Thomas", "Dylan Thomas", "Dylan Marlais Thomas"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this area of law, the Abercrombie spectrum favors the use of \"fanciful, arbitrary, or suggestive\" language, and the Polaroid and Sleekcra  tests set forth \"likelihood of confusion\" factors. The recently argued Supreme Court case Lee v. Tam, which was at the intersection of this area of law and the Constitution, involved an Asian American rock band called The Slants. In 2012, this area of law was held to be applicable to the red color used for the soles of Christian Louboutin (loo-boo-TAHN) shoes. The disparagement clause of the Lanham Act is the basis for the claim that the Washington Redskins should lose their protection under this area of law. For 10 points, name this area of intellectual property law that protects logos, words, and other forms of expression that companies use to identify their brands.", "answer": "trademark law [accept trademark protection; prompt on \"intellectual property law\" or \"IP law\" before \"intellectual\"]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>trademark</u></b> law [accept <b><u>trademark protection</u></b>; prompt on <u>intellectual property law</u> or <u>IP law\"</u> before \"intellectual]", "acceptable": ["trademark law", "trademark", "trademark protection"], "promptable": ["intellectual property law", "IP law\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A concerto for this instrument contains a \"war\" between the alternating keys of F major and E major that is exacerbated by a prominent snare-drum part and that supposedly re ected the bipolar nature of its dedicatee, Aage Oxenvad (AH-geh OX-en-vahd). Claude Debussy wrote his Premiere Rhapsodie as an exam piece for students of this instrument at the Paris Conservatory. A concerto for this instrument uses a dif cult cadenza to link its  rst movement back-to-back with its Latin jazz\u00c2\u2013in uenced second movement. Johannes Brahms dedicated two sonatas for this instrument to Richard Muhlfeld (REE-\"card\" MOOL-\"felt\"). Aaron Copland wrote a concerto for this instrument that was intended for Benny Goodman. For 10 points, what woodwind instrument plays the glissando that opens George Gershwin's Rhapsody in Blue?", "answer": "clarinet(s)", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>clarinet</u></b>", "acceptable": ["clarinet", "clarinet"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "s"}, {"question": "The mechanism for one type of this process begins with two methanes colliding and forming both a pentavalent (pen-tah-VAY-lent) and a trivalent carbon atom. This process is done in \"real time\" at atmospheric pressure by passing an inert gas through a needle electrode and keeping only metastable atoms. Another form of it relies on the evaporation of a Taylor cone. Recombination energy is the opposite of the energy for this process. Proteins are always treated to the \"so \" form of this process. A er being desorbed from the matrix by a laser, analytes undergo this process during MALDI (mahl-dee). This process forms the \"M plus dot\" species, which then fragments and gets de ected by a magnetic  eld, during mass spectrometry. For 10 points, name this process by which an atom loses an electron and becomes charged.", "answer": "ionization [or chemical ionization; accept electrospray ionization or matrix-assisted laser desorption ionization or word forms such as ionizing; prompt on \"mass spectrometry\" or \"mass spec\" or \"spectrometry\"]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>ionization</u></b> [or <b><u>chemical ionization</u></b>; accept <b><u>electrospray ionization</u></b> or <b><u>matrix-assisted laser desorption ionization</u></b> or <b><u>word forms such as ionizing</u></b>; prompt on <u>mass spectrometry</u> or <u>mass spec</u> or <u>spectrometry</u>]", "acceptable": ["ionization", "ionization", "chemical ionization", "electrospray ionization", "matrix-assisted laser desorption ionization", "word forms such as ionizing"], "promptable": ["mass spectrometry", "mass spec", "spectrometry"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A city that fought to protect these people built a trebuchet that squared off against a machine called the \"cat,\" inspiring a work by Raimon Escrivan (\"rye-MOAN\" ess-kree-VAHN) in which the two siege engines engage in a mock debate. Folquet de Marselha (\"foal\"-KAY de mar-\"SAIL\") helped set up a convent at Prouilhe (proo-EEL-uh) for women who le  this group to become Catholics. Guillaume Be\u0301libaste (gee-YOHM BAY-lee-bahst) was likely the last \"perfect\" of this group, a status he gained via the consolamentum sacrament. An order to \"kill them all, for God will know his own\" was issued by a papal legate before the residents of Be\u0301ziers (BAY-zee-eh) were massacred for sheltering these people. Raymond VI (\"the sixth\") of Toulouse was their chief ally in Innocent III's war against them. For 10 points, what heretical group of southern France was targeted by the Albigensian Crusade?", "answer": "Cathars [accept word forms such as Catharism; accept Albigensians before \"Albigensian\"]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Cathars</u></b> [accept <b><u>word forms such as Catharism</u></b>; accept <b><u>Albigensians</u></b> before \"Albigensian]", "acceptable": ["Cathars", "Cathars", "word forms such as Catharism", "Albigensians"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This book contends that, when a man loves a woman, he hates nature and rejects the \"human beneath the skin\" in a section titled \"We Artists.\" This book contains the line \"I wish to be a yes-sayer\" in a section advocating the uncompromising acceptance of reality. Five years a er this book was published, its author expanded it to include a   h section and an appendix of songs. One section of this book begins by noting that, a er Buddha's death, people would show his shadow in a cave for centuries and posits that, \"for millennia yet,\" people will do the same for another dead  gure. The concepts of amor fati (ah-\"MORE\" FAH-tee) and eternal recurrence were introduced in, for 10 points, what Friedrich Nietzsche (NEE-tchuh) book that preceded Thus Spake Zarathustra in its use of the phrase \"God is dead\"?", "answer": "The Gay Science [or Die Fro\u0308hliche Wissenscha0; or The Joyful Wisdom]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Gay Science</u></b> [or <b><u>Die Fro\u0308hliche Wissenscha0</u></b>; or <b><u>The Joyful Wisdom</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The Gay Science", "Gay Science", "Die Fro\u0308hliche Wissenscha0", "The Joyful Wisdom"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "These phenomena are described using the transverse\u00c2\u2013traceless gauge, in which one can derive the quadrupole formula. Detectors for these phenomena are described by sensitivity curves for a characteristic strain h over some timescale. These phenomena are generated when the quadrupole moment of a mass distribution changes in time, which is why their best-understood sources are inspiraling binaries. The existence of these phenomena was strongly suspected because the orbital decay of the Hulse\u00c2\u2013Taylor binary pulsar agreed with the predictions of general relativity. A binary black hole merger led to the LIGO (\"lie-go\") experiment's direct detection of, for 10 points, what phenomena that are the propagation of ripples in spacetime curvature?", "answer": "gravitational waves [accept gravitational radiation and gravity waves]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>gravitational waves</u></b> [accept <b><u>gravitational radiation</u></b> or <b><u>gravity waves</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["gravitational waves", "gravitational waves", "gravitational radiation", "gravity waves"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "According to the mythos of these beings, they were \"awakened\" a er Varda  nished populating the sky with stars. Beings of this type who saw the Two Trees were known as ones \"of light.\" These beings were summoned by the Valar to undertake the Great Journey to Valinor, which resulted in their \"sundering\" into groups called the Avari and the Eldar. In the Second and Third Ages, Oropher and Thranduil (OH-roh-\"fair\" and THRAHN-doo-eel) were beings of this type who joined the Last Alliance. The Sindar are one race of these beings, who more generally called themselves the Quendi (KWEN-dee). The dwarf Gimli carries on a rivalry with a being of this type who joins the Fellowship of the Ring and uses a bow as his main weapon. For 10 points, what mythical beings in the Lord of the Rings universe are exempli ed by Legolas?", "answer": "elves [or elf; accept more speci c answers including the word elf or elves such as forest elves; accept Quendi before \"Quendi\"]", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>elves</u></b> [or <b><u>elf</u></b>; accept <b><u>more speci c answers including the word elf</u></b> or <b><u>elves such as forest elves</u></b>; accept <b><u>Quendi</u></b> before \"Quendi]", "acceptable": ["elves", "elves", "elf", "more speci c answers including the word elf", "elves such as forest elves", "Quendi"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A play on this title names Michael Gorra's literary biography about the \"making of an American masterpiece.\" Chapter 42 of a novel with this title contains a modernist depiction of a woman's consciousness as she meditates on her marriage until 4 a.m. A poem with this title refers to the \"sky where Watteau hung a lady's slipper\" and asks \"what sort of man was Fragonard?\" That poem with this title by William Carlos Williams begins \"your thighs are appletrees whose blossoms touch the sky.\" This is the title of a novel in which Countess Gemini reveals that Patsy is the love child of Madame Merle and Gilbert Osmond, whom the protagonist marries a er rejecting the proposals of Lord Warburton and Caspar Goodwood. For 10 points, what title refers to Isabel Archer in a novel by Henry James?", "answer": "The Portrait of a Lady [or \"Portrait of a Lady\"; accept Portrait of a Novel: Henry James and the Making of an American Masterpiece before \"novel\"]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Portrait of a Lady</u></b> [or <b><u>Portrait of a Lady</u></b>; accept <b><u>Portrait of a Novel: Henry James</u></b> or the <b><u>Making of an American Masterpiece</u></b> before \"novel]", "acceptable": ["The Portrait of a Lady", "Portrait of a Lady", "Portrait of a Lady", "Portrait of a Novel: Henry James", "Making of an American Masterpiece"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An inhibitor of calcineurin (cal-sih-NOOR-in) named for this disease's candidate region suppresses V\u00c2\u00b7E\u00c2\u00b7G\u00c2\u00b7F, which is why people with this disease rarely get solid tumors. A cell adhesion molecule named for this disease in Drosophila (druh-SAHF-ih-luh) is a canonical example of alternative splicing. This disease is suggested by low serum levels of the metalloproteinase pappalysin (pap-uh-\"LICE\"-in). Though it's neither ALS nor Alzheimer's, this disease causes overexpression of S\u00c2\u00b7O\u00c2\u00b7D\u00c2\u00b71 and the amyloid precursor protein. People with this disease o en have transverse creases on their hands or white spots on the outside of their irises. The familial form of this disease is caused by a translocation; more commonly, it is caused by a nondisjunction of the smallest chromosome. For 10 points, name this disease, the trisomy of chromosome 21.", "answer": "Down syndrome [or Down's syndrome; accept DS; prompt on \"trisomy 21\" or other answers mentioning \"trisomy\" and \"chromosome 21\" before \"trisomy\"]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Down syndrome</u></b> [or <b><u>Down's syndrome</u></b>; accept <b><u>DS</u></b>; prompt on <u>trisomy 21</u> or <u>other answers mentioning \"trisomy</u> or <u>chromosome 21\"</u> before \"trisomy]", "acceptable": ["Down syndrome", "Down syndrome", "Down's syndrome", "DS"], "promptable": ["trisomy 21", "other answers mentioning \"trisomy", "chromosome 21\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}